Musa Adamu

+48 732 696 813 · musaduwa@rgmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/musa-duwa/ 27 Wrobleskiego, 51-627, Wroclaw, Poland

DATA ANALYST

I am a well-versed Python, SQL, spreadsheet, and Power BI data analyst. I am guite proficient with systems for efficient data analysis and have experience reading and analyzing data. I am skilled at creating performance measurements and tracking tools to help track and assess the current state of organizational improvement.

MY PORTFOLIO:

www.musaduwa.github.io

KEY COMPETENCIES

Data Analysis, Data Visualisation, Data Reporting, IT Support, and Software Development

TECHNICAL STACK

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE

Python,

Java

DATABASE

Oracle SQL, Google Bigquery **TOOLS**

PowerBI,

Microsoft Excel And Googlesheet,

Tableau

Google Looker; Jupyter Notebook,

Google Colab

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Tech Tanks Solutions IT Engineer

Nov. 2021 - Sept. 2022

Responsible for building technological products/services that meet customer needs, and also providing constant research for high-tech solutions to improve the company's product/services.

Accomplishments:

- I conducted a review of the current company website and implemented the new branding, design, user experience, and search engine optimization
- Analyzed the company sales data from 2018 to 2021 and identified the products and services that are generating more revenue and the ones that need improvements
- Trained clients on how to use the company's ERP system to ensure a smooth transition and streamline their business processes
- · Conducted market research and indentified technology that are relevant to the company target clients

Your Daily Store Online

Data Analyst And IT Support

May 2020 - Nov 2021

Managing YDS company's IT operations and infrastructure, and also applying technological systems and products to simplify internal business processes. The goal is to maximize day-to-day efficiency and productivity within the company, for instance, by automating complex tasks or enabling faster communication across departments, and analysiing data for decision making

Accomplishments:

- Analyzed the company sales data and identified the best-selling items, and the high-value customers of the company
- Evaluated the benefits and drawbacks of different systems options and make recommendations based on the budget and goal

Nigeria Communications Commission Student Internship

Feb. 2018 - Dec. 2018

Opportunity for career exploration and development, and learning new skills and organisational working experience.

Accomplishments:

- Engaged in Network, Computer System, and Printers Installation and troubleshooting.
- Ensured all website information are accurate and up to date

EDUCATION

Wroclaw University of Science And Technology

Masters of Science in Computer Engineering Oct. 2022 - Present

Abubakar Tafawa Balewa University

Bachelors of Technology in Computer Science Apr. 2015 - Feb. 2022

Grade: Distinction (4.59/5.00)

LANGUAGE LEVEL
• English • C2

• Polish • A1

CERTIFICATIONS

IBM DIGITAL EXPLORER IN DATA SCIENCE 2020

IBM DIGITAL EXPLORER IN ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE 2020

IBM DIGITAL EXPLORER IN BLOCKCHAIN 2020

INTERESTS

Machine Learning and Big Data Analysis, Research, Travelling, and Football